Finding Aid for the Sue Prosin Papers LSC.2225
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sue Prosin papers
1959-1986
LSC.2225
UCLA Library Special Collections
1.8 linear feet (2 boxes, 1 carton)
Sue Prosin was a social scientist who published studies on a range of topics like butch-femme relationships and attitudes of the Jewish community toward African-Americans. She attended San Fernando Valley State College (currenty California State University, Northridge) and was also an active member of the Daughters of Bilitis. This collection contains correspondence, research materials, and various writings by Prosin. The bulk of the collection focuses on her study of butch-femme lesbian relationships between 1960 and 1965.
Prosin, Sue
Conditions Governing Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
June Mazer Lesbian Archives, transfer, 2014. Original provenance unknown.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7404728
Sponsor
The June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.
Biography
Sue Prosin was a social scientist who published studies on a range of topics like butch-femme relationships and attitudes of the Jewish community toward African-Americans. She attended San Fernando Valley State College (now California State University, Northridge) and was also an active member of the Daughters of Bilitis. The original purpose of the Daughters of Bilitis (founded in 1955) was to counteract the isolation experienced by lesbians, although the organization later focused on educating lesbians about their rights and on lobbying efforts. Prosin died in 2002.
Scope and Content
This collection contains correspondence, research materials, and various writings by Sue Prosin. The bulk of the collection focuses on a study by Prosin of butch-femme lesbian relationships between 1960 and 1965.
Organization and Arrangement
Materials arranged by type.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Related Material
Daughters of Bilitis Records (Collection 1946). Available at Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA.; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives.; Prosin, Sue -- Archives.; Butch and femme (Lesbian culture)
- Coursework, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folders 1-2)
  Scope and Content
  Papers, drafts of papers, notes and research materials from Prosin's undergraduate course work.
- Planner, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Clippings, 1962-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Clippings of news stories concerning activism by Sue Prosin and about her mother, Frieda Trebor, the first occupational therapist in California.
- Assorted materials, 1961-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes a flyer, notes, and a card to June Mazer and Bunny MacCulloch.
- Daughters of Bilitis Second National Convention, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Prosin's resume, copies of several different articles, and other materials regarding the presentation of her paper "A Study in Minority Action" at the Daughters of Bilitis Second National Convention.
- "The Concept of the Lesbian, a Minority in Reverse" by Sue Prosin, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Drafts, correspondences, and notes for the publication of Prosin's article, presented at the Daughters of Bilitis Second National Convention under the title of "A Study in Minority Action."
- Resource books, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  The Blue Book: A Guide to Gay and Lesbian LA (1979) and LA Women's Yellow Pages (1977)
- Correspondence, circa 1965-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Negatives (photographs), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Recipes, poems, notes, circa 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Poems, clippings, notes and personal writings of Sue Prosin.
- Writings, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  "The Lesbian: A Study in Self-Image and Role Playing Patterns" and "The Concept of the Lesbian: A Minority in Reverse" by Sue Prosin.
- Butch-femme study, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folders 2-13)
  Contains notes on observations, research literature, research design materials, interviews with couples, data tabulation sheets, research proposals and survey materials for a study on butch-femme relationships and gendered dynamics by Sue Prosin.
- Audiovisual materials, 1960-1981 (Box 3)
  Includes twenty-three 1/4 inch audio reels pertaining to Prosin's butch-femme study. There is an additional audio reel container that is supposed to include the second reel of selections from Ruth Reid's "Dark Birth," but it is empty. Also includes three audiocassette tapes containing interviews with Sue Prosin.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.